Yves E. Hoebeke

+1 863 303-6367 yves.hoebeke@bytesupply.com https://yveshoebeke.github.io/

INTRODUCTION

For more than 25 years I have been working as a software engineer, mostly in Los Angeles and New York City.

My expertise is GO in conjunction with adjunct technologies such as JS, HTML, PostgreSQL, mongoDB, MySQL, AMQP, REST API and gRPC.

In the past I worked with C, NodeJS, Java, PHP, Assembly and some others I am no longer proficient in and are of diminished relevance.

I have a track record of building systems that have withstood the test of time; many of which are still running today after many years.

Interested in a full or part time GO developer position, preferably in a remote or hybrid setting.

PROFICIENCY/SKILLS

- · Go, Python, Tk, PHP, C, Java, NodeJS.
- CSS, HTML, JavaScript/JQuery.
- · MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis.
- AWS S3. AWS EC2, AMQP, REST, gRPC.
- Unix/Linux/MacOS, Apache, NGINX, Docker.
- No longer relevant: BASIC, COBOL, Fortran, RPG, ASM (Western Digital WD16, Motorola M680x0 and Z80 ISA's), P/OS, AMOS, C/PM, DOS.

SYNOPSIS of recent technology experience

- HTTP/TCP ServeMux, Gorilla/Mux, Gin.
- Json/XML Encoding/Decoding.
- Go routines / Mutex.
- · Blockchain.
- gRPC, RESTful APIs.
- Data encryption encoding/decoding.

EXPERIENCE

Contract services; Greenwich, CT & Haines City, FL - Current
 Took time off for personal reasons including a relocation, however, during that time performed contract work for:

Animal Vision Technologies - Collaboration on a mobile app to simulate visual perception of wildlife. Java/Kotlin and Swift.

Starlen & Associates - Blockchain based mechanism for document (property deeds mostly) integrity assurance. In GO with Fyne GUI.

- Engineer Core Services, Discovery; New York, NY 06/2019-09/2020
 Member of the core engineering team. Tasked to convert legacy PHP libraries to Go and the inception of SSAI (Server Side Ad Insertion). REST and gRPC interfaces for client consumption and industry data ingestion in asynchronous fashion.
- Software Engineer, Acuity; New York, NY 11/2017-07/2019
 Architected a Clinical Documentation Improvement (CDI) intranet application in Go, allowing dedicated medical personnel to collaborate and data transfer API to a Tableau server for data visualization. Some HTML/JS involved.
- Software Engineer, eTouches; Norwalk, CT 02/2016-03/2017
 Member of the DevOps group, as such I am primarily responsible for augmenting existing software. The application consists of a mix of PHP Laravel/Yii and custom written modules. The application allows customers to organize participation and attendance in various industry events and expositions.
- Software Engineer, Benchmark Educ.; New Rochelle, NY 12/2014-01/2016
 Part of the IT internal engineering group. Predominately architected the implementation, ingestion, validation and delivery system for educational products primarily using Laravel framework with AMQP queueing as a Producer with Consumer scripts in PHP, Python and nodeJS.
- Lead Application Engineer, MedAdherence; Stamford, CT 01/2013-11/2014
 Implemented a number of API points to retrieve data from various biometric data collection devices and set up standardized data structures for retrieval by medical research centers. PHP in a Codelgniter framework.

EDUCATION

- Royal Athenaeum Ghent, Belgium Humanities & Science. 1971 1974
- Extracurricular at IBM Belgium, Antwerp, Belgium. 1973 1974
- Belgian Armed Forces, Field Artillery School, Brasschaat, Belgium. 1975

OTHER CAREER RESPONSIBILITIES

- Program development, testing, staging, implementation and evaluation.
- Strategic planning, building coalitions and strategic partnerships.
- Development of organizational policies and operational controls.
- Staff hiring, supervision, evaluation and motivation.

MISCELLANEOUS

- Languages (in order of fluency): English, Dutch, Spanish, French and German.
- EU (Belgium) Passport holder with I-551 ("green card") since 1987.
- Military service: Lieutenant 2nd Artillery Regiment NATO Lüdenscheid, BRD (West-Germany).
- FAA certification: CMEL/IFR CFI/I DX.